Hi guys, welcome to the IELTS Reading course.
I'm Francois, your instructor in this course.
Before learning the knowledge and skills to handle
challenging IELTS reading questions, we're going to get
to know a little bit about our IELTS
reading tests and have an overview of the course.
I'm very excited to share valuable knowledge with
you and I hope you're also excited to
learn high quality lessons prepared by the academic team at PREP.
So are you ready?
Let's get started.
First, let's take a look at the test time for IELTS reading.
For paper-based tests, you have 60 minutes
to read, answer questions and transfer your answers
to the answer sheet.
Please note that in IELTS reading tests,
we don't have 10 minutes to transfer answers to
the answer sheet like in the listening tests.
Therefore, you need to read and transfer your
answers at the same time.
Similarly, for computer-based tests, you have 60
minutes to read and answer questions and you
need to type your answers directly onto the computer.
Number of questions.
About the number of questions, an IELTS reading
test has 40 questions, which are divided into
three passages with increasing difficulty.
Purpose.
An IELTS academic reading test assesses the following
aspects of your reading skills.
Identify the main idea, understand details, logical arguments
and recognize the writer's opinion, attitude and purpose.
Content of reading passages.
Next, the content of reading passages are often
taken from books, journals, magazines and newspapers and
written by native speakers in an academic style.
These passages have been selected for non-specialist
audience, but are appropriate for people entering university
courses or seeking professional registration.
Common question types.
About common question types in IELTS reading tests,
you have to understand all of them.
Number one, completion.
Sentence completion, table completion, flowchart completion, diagram
completion, summary completion and note completion.
Two, short answer questions.
Answer questions with short words taken from the passage.
Three, matching.
Matching headings, matching information
Matching features, matching sentence endings.
Four, multiple choice questions.
Questions with single answer and questions with multiple answers.
Five, True, False, Not Given and Yes, No, Not Given.
These question types will be explained in detail
later in the course and based on the order above.
Stay tuned.
How to calculate IELTS reading band scores.
So, how can you calculate your IELTS reading band score?
Please look at the table of the reading
band score in the IELTS academic test from
the official website of IELTS.
You already know how many correct answers you
have to get, don't you?
After having an overview of IELTS reading tests,
let's see what our reading course will provide you with.
Course goals.
Help you understand the format of IELTS reading tests.
Help you aim for a six or higher
reading band score after the course.
Help you master six necessary skills to improve
your reading skills.
Help you learn more than 100 B1 words
through reading passages suitable for intermediate learners.
Now, let's find out what the effective study
methods for this intermediate reading course are.
For today, I suggest you follow the following three steps.
Step one.
Watch the video attentively.
Take notes and complete tasks in the video.
Step two.
Do the exercises of each lesson.
And last but not least, step three.
Create a table of mistakes and a vocabulary list.
This third step is really important for both
your regular studies and exam preparation.
In short, steps one and two focus mostly
on task awareness, which is about getting used
to the test format, managing your time, and
checking your accuracy.
So, if you only focus on these tasks
and then move on to another reading passage,
you will not boost your vocabulary, which is
the key factor for score improvement.
That's why, for step three, we will delve
deeper into not only vocabulary expansion, but also
error analysis, where we synthesize the mistakes, helping
you pay more attention to them, to avoid
repeating the same mistakes in other exercises.
You can create a table of mistakes with
the following template.
In the column Date, you can write the
date when you did the test to keep
track of your learning progress.
In the column Passage, you can write the
lesson's name in this course, or the book title,
unit title, the topic you are studying
in supplementary books to help you study the
course better, if you have any.
In the column Score, you can write your
score to self-evaluate your learning process.
In the column Question, you can write the
question number or a brief summary of the
question type so that you can easily review it later.
The column Mistake will be about the mistakes
you find after receiving corrections or self-checking the answers.
And the final column aims to suggest solutions.
By doing this, we can track our learning
progress over time to see if there are
any repeated mistakes, any score improvements, or new solutions.
Regarding making a vocabulary list, because in a
reading passage, there may be a lot of
new words, and it is very difficult for
us to memorize them all, or there are
specialized words which are a little practical, we
should prioritize learning vocabulary based on the following order.
Learn words in questions and in information areas
containing the answers in paragraphs.
In the IELTS exam, the information in the
passage is often expressed in a different way
from the questions.
The act of using various expressions is called
paraphrase.
Therefore, you are learning and familiarizing yourself with
techniques for paraphrasing used by test makers.
Also, you are learning how to apply them
to your writing skills.
For example, in the reading passage, there is
a question below.
Any trees that are ... should be left to
grow as they add to the variety of
species in the forest.
The information area containing the answer in the paragraph is.
Finally, rare species of trees in a forest
should also stay behind as they add to
its structural diversity.
The keyword variety in the question is similar to diversity.
If you don't know these two words, then
you should prioritize learning them.
If you already know all those words, you
can spend time reading the whole passage and
learn essential words in sentences.
If you don't know the meaning of these
ones, it's really hard for you to guess
or understand the meanings of the sentences containing them.
Here is an example of how I organize
my vocabulary list.
In the column Word, you can write down
the word you need to learn, its word
form and pronunciation to understand and use it
correctly in reading and other skills.
In the column Synonyms or Paraphrases in the
paragraph, you can write down the word or
phrase the writer used to paraphrase the word
you need to learn.
In the column Meaning, you can write down
its meaning in English and/or your first language.
It would be best if you write it
in English because by doing that, you can
understand its meaning in the most correct way.
In the column Example, you can form sentences
which are related to the topic you are
learning or use them in your writing and speaking.
For example, in the vocabulary list, I wrote
a sample sentence for introduction of an IELTS
Writing task 2 essay.
It's like killing two birds in one stone,
isn't it?
You can also search for keywords of the
reading passages topic on Google or any task
2 question related to the topic to form
sentences with the words you've just learned and
answer that question.
These are the basic steps that help you
to make the most of the resources from
the IELTS intermediate reading course
and improve your score and skills.
Please note that if you focus on practicing
IELTS tests right away, it may be overwhelming
at first because you can encounter lots of new words.
If any of you experience this situation, I
suggest you search for reading passages in intermediate
level books and learn new vocabulary from those
texts to improve your reading skills.
Now, I believe that you are all well prepared.
Let's kick off this journey together.
I'm teacher Francois and I'll see you again
in the very first lesson.
Goodbye.